<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-05T23:07:41+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">She Goes Places And Sees Things</title><subtitle>Tales of some adventures in New Zealand and beyond...</subtitle><entry><title type="html">MELBOURNE TO CAIRNS IN 30 DAYS - PART TWO</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/australia/travel/2016/12/07/melbourne-to-cairns-in-30-days-part-two.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MELBOURNE TO CAIRNS IN 30 DAYS - PART TWO" /><published>2016-12-07T18:05:07+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T18:05:07+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/australia/travel/2016/12/07/melbourne-to-cairns-in-30-days-part-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/australia/travel/2016/12/07/melbourne-to-cairns-in-30-days-part-two.html">&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;THE JOURNEY, PART TWO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Surfers Paradise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/surfersparadise.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The beach, Surfers Paradise&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Despite its name, this town is a long way from my idea of paradise. Perhaps it is decent for surfing, and I have met people who said they had an awesome time here, but it seemed to me like a party town on steroids and the literal shadow cast over the beach by the high-rise buildings is not exactly pretty. I only spent less than 24 hours there so maybe I missed all the good bits, but first impressions do make their mark! I'll leave it up to you to visit and decide whether it's the best fun you've ever had or hell on earth…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Fraser Island&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;A driving tour on this incredible island is an absolute must-do on the east coast. It is the world's largest sand island, so think of it as one massive sand dune! Despite all the sand, quite a bit of the island is forest and home to lots of animals, including the dingo, which you are pretty likely to spot during a visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/fraserconvoy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Driving convoy, Fraser Island&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;I started from Rainbow Beach for my two-night trip, which involved being split into groups to drive 4x4's, in convoy, all around the island. What made it so awesome was that everyone got a turn at driving, so it was far more hands-on (and hands definitely were on the steering wheel at all times driving through the sand!) than most tours. Accommodation was a large camp near the beach, fully enclosed by a dingo fence, and my nights there were very much goon-and-campfire kind of nights! One of the best places is Lake McKenzie, the water forming an incredible gradient from crystal clear to deep blue, although unfortunately, it was raining when I visited so my photos aren't quite as impressive as others. Whatever the time of year though, make sure you don't miss out on this fantastic experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lakemckenzie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lake Mckenzie&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;1770 and Agnes Water&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/1770.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1770 sunset&quot; width=&quot;337&quot; height=&quot;398&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Pretty much the only reason for coming here is the Scooteroo tour, an afternoon of motorbiking, kangaroo-spotting and watching the sun set over the sea. Before they let you loose on the roads, they give everyone a quick practise at riding a motorbike around a little circuit they've got set up on the grass. Once they're satisfied, you all don helmets and leather jackets and off you go. Even if they won't let you ride your own bike, like me (apparently being able to turn corners is important, who knew?!), you can be what they call a 'koala' and hop on the back with one of the leaders. I actually thought this was more fun anyway as it meant I got to go faster and get a better look at the kangaroos without having to focus on the driving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;The Whitsundays&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/tongarra.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tongarra, Whitehaven Beach&quot; width=&quot;380&quot; height=&quot;192&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;The Whitsundays, 74 islands of paradise dotted through the coral sea. These islands are very popular for sailing trips from Airlie Beach and even in autumn when I visited, they were still pretty spectacular. I spent two nights sailing on a catamaran, the Tongarra, weaving around some of the islands, snorkelling and only occasionally hiding from the rain. One of my favourite bits was being able to sleep out on deck under canopies put up by the two-man crew. The sea was the first thing I saw and heard each morning and I just wish I could wake up like that every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/P5240899.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Whitehaven Beach, Whitsunday Island&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Possibly one of the most famous beaches in Australia, Whitehaven Beach is found on Whitsunday Island and is truly stunning. It was raining when I visited, but the blue and white swirls of sand and sea were still amazing to see, even with the stormy skies. I would definitely recommend this to anyone travelling the east coast, it was so much fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Cairns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;After almost a month of travelling, I finally arrived in Cairns! Despite being autumn, Cairns still had a distinctly tropical feeling, as you might expect from the far north of Queensland. The impression I got here was of a pretty major party town, lots of backpackers drinking all night and then sunbathing by the lagoon nursing a hangover. Gilligan's, a hostel well-known for its party atmosphere, seemed to be the place to be and although I chose not to stay there, I did pay it a visit. Now, don't get me wrong, I enjoy a night out but I'm not so much the short-skirt-and-stilettos-flashing-my-knickers-on-the-pavement kind of girl so I'm not sure I fully appreciated the crazy party vibe as much as other people! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/barrierreef.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Great Barrier Reef&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Scuba diving on the Great Barrier Reef however, was one of the highlights of my entire trip. It was my first time diving and while I was actually pretty scared, swimming around among the corals and fish was just incredible. If I'd had more time here I would have definitely been keen to give it another go though and perhaps do a PADI course. Actually seeing the natural beauty of the reef though makes it feel so much more real to hear of the damage caused by coral bleaching and climate change. It's so important to take care of this beautiful structure before it's too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;A trip up to the Daintree Rainforest and Cape Tribulation, known as the point where the rainforest meets the ocean, is also a must-do when visiting Cairns. The rainforest is an amazing place, full of strange-looking plants and animals, including crocodiles and cassowaries, that look like they haven't changed in millions of years. I remember thinking while walking along a board-walk trail near the hostel that I wouldn't be surprised if a dinosaur came strolling (do dinosaurs stroll?) around the corner! Apparently also in the forests here are little ants, which when you lick them taste like lemon sherbet, however, I didn't trust myself to pick the right ones so maybe next time…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float:center; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/P5300134.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Where the rainforest meets the reef&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;While I saw and did a lot during my month in Australia, I certainly left feeling like I wasn't finished with the country, which I reckon is a good thing. There is still so much more that I want to see, so I will definitely be returning one day. There are still places on the east coast that I would love to visit, such as the Blue Mountains but I think next on my list would have to be Western Australia...&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Adventure" /><category term="Australia" /><category term="East Coast" /><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html">THE JOURNEY, PART TWO Surfers Paradise</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MELBOURNE TO CAIRNS IN 30 DAYS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/australia/travel/2016/12/02/melbourne-to-cairns-in-30-days.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MELBOURNE TO CAIRNS IN 30 DAYS" /><published>2016-12-02T23:10:29+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-02T23:10:29+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/australia/travel/2016/12/02/melbourne-to-cairns-in-30-days</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/australia/travel/2016/12/02/melbourne-to-cairns-in-30-days.html">&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;So, a month to travel between two cities may sound like a lot...but not when it's the Australian East Coast! My adventures here last year saw me spend 30 days travelling the 3000km from Melbourne, in southern Victoria, all the way up to Cairns in northern Queensland. In hindsight, I would have liked to have had a lot more time travelling this well-trodden backpacker route, a few months or a year perhaps! What I did have, however, was four weeks of action-packed travelling, very much going places and seeing things!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;The Country&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;One of the main things which struck me about Australia was its size. If you come from the UK, then the scale of the country is pretty incomprehensible. Just the 3000km from Melbourne to Cairns, which isn't even the most-northerly point, is three times longer than the UK, and it's over 4000km across remote outback over to the west coast. Especially as I had just come from New Zealand, these distances just blew my mind and it's easy to forget when planning on a map that whole days are going to be taken up with bus journeys. What's more, the east coast route is still a pretty small part of Australia, yes it's got three of the big cities, Melbourne, Sydney and Brisbane, but what about Western Australia? The Northern Territory? South Australia? Tasmania? With the huge popularity of the east coast, most of the rest of the country can sometimes, I think, be overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;The Journey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Melbourne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/P1010548 (2).JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Melbourne city centre&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float:right; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/stkilda.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;St Kilda sunset&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;I began my journey at the beginning of May, with a few days in Melbourne. Having just left the Kiwi autumn, it felt pretty warm, although obviously it wasn't, by Australian standards - I've learnt from the few Aussies I've met, even the ones that weren't born and bred there, that there is a big difference in what they would call a warm day! Anyway, Melbourne is a great city to visit. There are cafés, bars and shops galore, nestled in funky little laneways, there's trams, lots of green spaces and the beach not far away. I spent my time there with a visit to St Kilda beach to see the penguins come out at sunset (NB. I was kind of hoping for black and white penguins, the St Kilda variety are somewhat smaller, and bluer!), a trip to the MCG stadium to watch an Australian Rules Football match (Go Carlton!) and a bus ride along the Great Ocean Road. As well as getting to see the famous not-quite-twelve Twelve Apostles, this bus trip was also the only time I got to see koalas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Sydney&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/P5050729.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Sydney Harbour&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Next up was Sydney, after an all-night bus anyway. I loved Sydney, four days there really wasn't enough for me, I could have easily stayed. One of the best vantage points I found of the famous harbour was from the top of the Sydney Harbour Bridge, the water, the city skyline, the ferries and the Botanic Gardens makes an excellent view, although obviously you won't get to see the bridge at the same time! One of the best things I did was the walk from Coogee to Bondi, a coastal path which takes a couple hours and has some brilliant views. However, I did think that Bondi Beach was a little overrated, sure the pool right by the ocean is pretty cool, but otherwise, it just looked like a beach to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/P5060759.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Bondi Beach&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;If you want to get out of the city centre, then visit Manly. I got the ferry over one evening and watched the sun set over the beach, it was very pretty and is definitely somewhere I'd go back to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/manly.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Manly&quot; width=&quot;421&quot; height=&quot;299&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Byron Bay&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/minyon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Minyon Falls&quot; width=&quot;392&quot; height=&quot;294&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Very popular with surfer types, Byron Bay is all about the beach. A small town with a chilled-out vibe, it's easy to see why it's so popular with backpackers, and because of this, there are plenty of bars and shops around to keep you busy, if you want to be busy that is. Unfortunately I didn't have enough time here to really explore, although I did make it out to nearby Minyon Falls, a pretty spectacular waterfall, and to the Channon Market, a quirky hippie craft market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Look out for The Journey, Part Two, coming soon...&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Adventure" /><category term="Australia" /><category term="East Coast" /><category term="Solo travel" /><category term="Travel" /><summary type="html">So, a month to travel between two cities may sound like a lot...but not when it's the Australian East Coast! My adventures here last year saw me spend 30 days travelling the 3000km from Melbourne, in southern Victoria, all the way up to Cairns in northern Queensland. In hindsight, I would have liked to have had a lot more time travelling this well-trodden backpacker route, a few months or a year perhaps! What I did have, however, was four weeks of action-packed travelling, very much going places and seeing things!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BEST BRITISH CITIES</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2016/11/08/best-british-cities.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BEST BRITISH CITIES" /><published>2016-11-08T17:15:51+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-08T17:15:51+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2016/11/08/best-british-cities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2016/11/08/best-british-cities.html">&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Having fairly recently moved back to the UK after more than a year abroad, I have found, in some ways, a renewed appreciation for my home country. Over the last few weeks, I've visited a few British cities including a couple I hadn't been to before, so, here is a round-up of my favourite cities in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;SHEFFIELD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/IMG_2543-1-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view of Sheffield&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;The City of Steel is one of my all-time favourite cities. I lived there for four years while at Uni, so I got to know it pretty well. I think a common perception of Sheffield is that it is still stuck in its highly industrial past and isn't somewhere a lot of people might think of visiting, which is a shame. In recent years, the city has been going through big regeneration and, while it is still a little rough around the edges as most large cities are, it is now a lovely place to live or visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;One of my favourite things about the city is its green-ness and its proximity to the Peak District. As a keen runner, I loved spending summer (and even winter) evenings pounding the trails just a couple of miles outside the city centre, the beautiful Rivelin Valley being a particular favourite. Even the city itself has no shortage of outdoor space and Endcliffe Park, Weston Park and Crookes Valley Park are all excellent places to spend a sunny afternoon or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/DSCF5788-2-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view over the Peak District&quot; width=&quot;389&quot; height=&quot;292&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Sheffield also boasts an excellent entertainment scene, especially for music fans, and is home to bands including the Arctic Monkeys, Pulp and The Human League. One of my personal favourite clubs, the Leadmill, hosts a lot of live music nights and at least when I went there, used to play a lot of good indie music. The Nottingham House pub is worth a visit too for its pies and pub quiz! The city also has a strong sporting history and is home to two professional football teams, the Sheffield Steelers ice hockey team, as well as a few famous Olympians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;EDINBURGH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;I may have only recently visited Edinburgh for the first time but it has quickly found a place among my favourite cities. Some of the best bits include the cobbled streets of the Old Town, the walk up to Arthur's Seat and the hugely varied nightlife, but check out my full article about it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shegoesplacesandseesthings.com/travel/edinburgh-a-scottish-adventure/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;CAMBRIDGE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cambridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A sunny day by the river in Cambridge&quot; width=&quot;370&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;As my home town, I felt it really should occupy a top spot in this list. The city is home to one of the oldest and best Universities in the world and is a very popular tourist destination for visitors to the UK. While pretty all year round, I'd say Cambridge is at its best (although definitely most busy) in the summer when an afternoon of punting or a stroll to Grantchester are both top activities. Punting especially is very popular and you can either hire your own or have a punt chauffeur to do it for you whilst they talk you through a bit of Cambridge history... Just don't necessarily believe all of their (occasionally made-up) stories!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Definitely don't forget to take a camera for a visit to Cambridge. Some of the most popular sights include Kings College Chapel, The Backs and the Corpus 'Grasshopper' Clock outside the Corpus Christi library, which features flashing lights instead of hands and is interesting to see, if you can get close enough!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;As an old city, Cambridge has some excellent old drinking establishments. A couple of the famous ones include The Eagle, where Watson and Crick are said to have first drawn the structure of DNA, and The Pickerel, which claims to be among Cambridge's oldest, dating back to the 1500s. If you can, try to catch a show at the Footlights, the University's amateur theatre group at the ADC Theatre. Although it sells out way in advance, their Christmas pantomine is very good and they regularly put on comedy nights during term time. The Footlights is known for producing some excellent talent, and notable alumni include Stephen Fry, Hugh Laurie, David Mitchell, Mel Giedroyc and Sue Perkins, several members of Monty Python, and The Inbetweeners' Simon Bird, among many, many more! Check out this Wikipedia list &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_former_Footlights_members&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;BATH&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/180-247x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pulteney Bridge at night time&quot; width=&quot;318&quot; height=&quot;387&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Although I have visited Bath quite a few times, a recent weekend spent there is the reason I have included it among my favourites. Although mainly famous for the Roman Baths, many of the city's well-known areas were built in the Georgian era and a lot of the city today is defined by this sort of architecture. A small city, Bath is easy to wander around and some of the best sightseeing includes Bath Abbey, the Royal Crescent and Pulteney Bridge, which is one of only very few to have shops on both sides. Although you can't see it from the bridge, the weir below it is definitely worthy of a photo, especially at night when the surrounding area is all lit up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;There is also no shortage of shops, pubs and restaurants in the city centre, with fairly recently revamped shopping streets near to the train station which unless you look closely, you would struggle to tell apart from the old Georgian buildings. One downside to Bath however, is that it is pretty eye-wateringly expensive. Drinks and dinner, for example, are not cheap, with a pint of something setting you back at least £4-5. A quick glance in an estate agent's window (there are lots of them!) at the many city centre properties over £1 million will show you that Bath is a very desirable place indeed!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Having fairly recently moved back to the UK after more than a year abroad, I have found, in some ways, a renewed appreciation for my home country. Over the last few weeks, I've visited a few British cities including a couple I hadn't been to before, so, here is a round-up of my favourite cities in Britain.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">THE JOYS OF TRAVELLING SOLO</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2016/10/11/the-joys-of-travelling-solo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="THE JOYS OF TRAVELLING SOLO" /><published>2016-10-11T14:25:31+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-11T14:25:31+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2016/10/11/the-joys-of-travelling-solo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2016/10/11/the-joys-of-travelling-solo.html">&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;A few years ago, I never thought that solo travelling would be for me. I've always had an independent streak but never thought I'd enjoy travelling by myself. When, at the start of 2015, I made the leap to explore New Zealand and Australia, almost everyone seemed stunned that I was going to go alone, and okay, I was a little bit scared! After I'd got over the initial culture shock however, I quickly found that the whole solo travelling thing really is a lot of fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Hostels make it so easy to meet people, I mean, there's usually at least 5 others in your dorm, sometimes into double figures! Chatting to them when you arrive, asking what people are up to that night, you'll often find that most people are keen for a new drinking buddy! Or, something I never thought I'd be happy to do, head to the hostel bar by yourself, see who's there; I've had some pretty interesting conversations doing this! I remember once up in northern Queensland, I was sitting in a bar watching an Aussie rules football match and got chatting to some local guys about it. I enjoy the sport, but I'm not a huge fan and I ended up having to pretend to know what they were on about when they started asking what I thought of their team's new manager's game strategy! But hey, it was fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;When travelling by yourself, it's nice not to have to be tied down to someone else's plans and you don't feel like you have to do things because someone else wants to. Obviously it's good to have people to spend time with, but if new friends don't fancy that day trip then you don't feel like you have to please them and you know that there will be others to chat to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Something I also find is really important is to be positive and open to doing things. Try not to say 'no' to things for no reason, if a new friend asks if you want to go to the hostel bar, say 'yes', you never know where the evening will take you or who you may meet! Of course, when I say this, I'm talking about reasonable things. If you really don't want to do something, if something is just outright dangerous, or if someone makes you feel uncomfortable then absolutely say 'no' and don't feel guilty for a second. I'm not suggesting that you should jump off a cliff because someone thinks it would be fun, or go home with the first person who looks at you, just to have an open and positive outlook. I feel I've learnt a lot from observing how people talk to me and how my friends make friends with others while travelling and I try to emulate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;I know that over the last couple of years since I first started travelling, I've changed a lot. It has made me more confident and open and has instilled a feeling of being capable of doing so much more. Meeting people from around the world means you learn so much about different countries and some of my closest friends now, I met whilst travelling. If you want to go explore the world solo, then don't feel like you can't and just go for it...a lot of people you meet will be in a similar boat!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Solo travel" /><summary type="html">A few years ago, I never thought that solo travelling would be for me. I've always had an independent streak but never thought I'd enjoy travelling by myself. When, at the start of 2015, I made the leap to explore New Zealand and Australia, almost everyone seemed stunned that I was going to go alone, and okay, I was a little bit scared! After I'd got over the initial culture shock however, I quickly found that the whole solo travelling thing really is a lot of fun!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EDINBURGH - A SCOTTISH ADVENTURE!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/scotland/travel/2016/10/10/edinburgh-a-scottish-adventure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EDINBURGH - A SCOTTISH ADVENTURE!" /><published>2016-10-10T09:01:22+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-10T09:01:22+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/scotland/travel/2016/10/10/edinburgh-a-scottish-adventure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/scotland/travel/2016/10/10/edinburgh-a-scottish-adventure.html">&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/royalmile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royal Mile&quot; width=&quot;352&quot; height=&quot;397&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Edinburgh, the capital city of Scotland located on the banks of the Firth of Forth, home to the Scottish Parliament, the world-famous Fringe festival and the destination of my latest travelling adventure. It occurred to me earlier this year, that I have now seen far more of New Zealand than I have done of my own country, the United Kingdom, and so I have made it a mission to rectify this, beginning with Scotland. I spent five days here, which was plenty of time to see the city of Edinburgh. Home to some half a million people, Edinburgh is divided into the Old Town and the New Town, separated by Princes Street Gardens. While the New Town is nice enough, the Old Town is where it's really at, in my opinion at least. Think cobbled streets, lanes, stone buildings hundreds of years old, quirky cafés and shops. The atmosphere reminded me of European towns such as Bruges or Amsterdam, not quite what I expected of Scotland!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;See The Sights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/edinburghcastle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Edinburgh Castle&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Some of the city's major attractions include Edinburgh Castle, Holyrood Palace, Calton Hill and Arthur's Seat, and are all well worth a visit. Edinburgh Castle, which dates from the 12th Century, perches high above the city at the top of the Royal Mile and can't really be missed! Even if you don't fancy paying the entrance fee, you can still cross the bridge into the castle's outer walls and the views over the Old Town are worthy of a photo or two!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/holyroodpalace.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Holyrood Palace&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;250&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;At the opposite end of the Royal Mile which, somewhat confusingly, is just over a mile long, sits Holyrood Palace, the Queen's official Scottish residence. The palace is on the edge of Holyrood Park and provides excellent views of Arthur's Seat, the extinct volcano towering 250m above the city. Several paths will take you to the summit, which apart from a little scrambling at the end, is a do-able walk for most. Make sure to take a camera for the panoramic views over the city and the Firth of Forth, and definitely a jumper for the cold wind at the top! Calton Hill, accessible from the New Town, is also another fantastic vantage point, meant to be especially pretty at sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/arthursseat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arthur's Seat&quot; width=&quot;526&quot; height=&quot;189&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float:right; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/tomriddle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tom Riddle&quot; width=&quot;170&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Other attractions include the Scottish Parliament, opposite Holyrood Palace. Certain areas of the building are open to the public and you can attend a short talk which mainly explains the somewhat avant-garde architecture! The National Museum of Scotland is also worth a visit and make sure to head up to the outdoor terrace on the 7th floor for more excellent city views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;For Harry Potter fans, check out the Greyfriars cemetery, just off the Grassmarket in the Old Town. Apparently a favourite walking location of J K Rowling, have a look for the head stone bearing the name Tom Riddle, supposedly her inspiration for Lord Voldemort himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;A Day Trip To The Highlands&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;If you can spare the time, I would definitely recommend venturing out into the Scottish Highlands. There are several companies offering popular day trips, most for around £50-60. I chose a trip up to Loch Ness, and although it included a lot of driving time, the gorgeous weather really showed off the landscape! Look out for Doune Castle which was used as a major filming location in the 1970's film Monty Python and The Holy Grail. Loch Ness itself is an impressive sight and evoked memories of the sounds and fjords of New Zealand with the steep, green hills rising from the dark water. While not the biggest of the Scottish lochs, Loch Ness holds the most water; at about 35 km long and around 200m deep, it's easy to imagine that old Nessie may be lurking in there somewhere. From Fort Augustus, take an hour-long boat trip out onto the Loch to really get a sense of the sheer scale of your surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lochness.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loch Ness&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Party Time!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Edinburgh, I discovered, has a pretty decent nightlife. I spent a few nights checking out the pubs and bars of the Grassmarket and Cowgate, and there is quite a choice! From old, traditional pubs to flashier bars, Irish pubs, salsa bars, live music pubs and five-storey dance clubs, there seems to be something for everyone. Organised bar crawls give you a taste of what's going on and are an excellent way to meet new friends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;If you've never been to Edinburgh, then I recommend that you do so. Easily reached by train or plane and with plenty of places to stay, it's definitely a good city break option. While there is enough to keep you busy, it would be easy to fit into a weekend away.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Capital" /><category term="Edinburgh" /><category term="Scotland" /><summary type="html">Edinburgh, the capital city of Scotland located on the banks of the Firth of Forth, home to the Scottish Parliament, the world-famous Fringe festival and the destination of my latest travelling adventure. It occurred to me earlier this year, that I have now seen far more of New Zealand than I have done of my own country, the United Kingdom, and so I have made it a mission to rectify this, beginning with Scotland. I spent five days here, which was plenty of time to see the city of Edinburgh. Home to some half a million people, Edinburgh is divided into the Old Town and the New Town, separated by Princes Street Gardens. While the New Town is nice enough, the Old Town is where it's really at, in my opinion at least. Think cobbled streets, lanes, stone buildings hundreds of years old, quirky cafés and shops. The atmosphere reminded me of European towns such as Bruges or Amsterdam, not quite what I expected of Scotland! &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Marathon Experiment - Conclusion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/marathons/running/2016/10/09/marathon-number-2-a-succesful-experiment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Marathon Experiment - Conclusion" /><published>2016-10-09T20:51:13+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T20:51:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/marathons/running/2016/10/09/marathon-number-2-a-succesful-experiment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/marathons/running/2016/10/09/marathon-number-2-a-succesful-experiment.html">&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;I did it! I completed marathon no.2 in Bournemouth last weekend. After a slightly experimental approach to training, I think it's fair to say that this marathon was a success. Finishing in 4 hours and 8 minutes, I was initially disappointed to have not managed a personal best, but in hindsight, I'm not too worried about the extra 3 minutes over a much more undulating course. Generally, I ran much better this time around, I felt strong until just over 20 miles whereas last time I was feeling it by mile 14, so not hitting quite such a vicious wall was pleasing! First time around, I ended up doing quite a lot of walking in the later stages, but this time I only walked through the later water stations so as to avoid the drowning sensation of drinking out of a cup whilst running. I kept to my goal splits fairly well, maybe running up to 10 seconds per km faster but still feeling comfortable. After a slight drop in motivation after realising, with 3.5 miles to go and only 20 minutes to beat my time, that I wasn't going to set a personal best, I managed a strong last mile to power over the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;So, my different training approach was, for me, a success. Slightly lower training mileage meant that I avoided any injuries or even niggles, I wasn't tired by race day - in fact, I felt strong and ready to go - and I was suitably restrained during my taper fortnight. In future, I think I'll continue with this style of training plan and continue to tweak it, until I really get it right!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I did it! I completed marathon no.2 in Bournemouth last weekend. After a slightly experimental approach to training, I think it's fair to say that this marathon was a success. Finishing in 4 hours and 8 minutes, I was initially disappointed to have not managed a personal best, but in hindsight, I'm not too worried about the extra 3 minutes over a much more undulating course. Generally, I ran much better this time around, I felt strong until just over 20 miles whereas last time I was feeling it by mile 14, so not hitting quite such a vicious wall was pleasing! First time around, I ended up doing quite a lot of walking in the later stages, but this time I only walked through the later water stations so as to avoid the drowning sensation of drinking out of a cup whilst running. I kept to my goal splits fairly well, maybe running up to 10 seconds per km faster but still feeling comfortable. After a slight drop in motivation after realising, with 3.5 miles to go and only 20 minutes to beat my time, that I wasn't going to set a personal best, I managed a strong last mile to power over the line.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Marathon Number 2 - The Experiment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/marathons/running/2016/08/30/marathon-number-2-the-experiment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Marathon Number 2 - The Experiment" /><published>2016-08-30T18:19:07+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-30T18:19:07+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/marathons/running/2016/08/30/marathon-number-2-the-experiment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/marathons/running/2016/08/30/marathon-number-2-the-experiment.html">&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;So, a little while ago I decided it was time to attempt another marathon. As you'll know if you've read my previous post &lt;a href=&quot;https://distancealltheway.wordpress.com/2015/12/11/my-first-marathon/&quot;&gt;My first marathon&lt;/a&gt;, I ran the Nottingham marathon almost exactly two years ago and in hindsight, I made a lot of rookie errors. This time, with the experience of one under my running belt, I want to try to do my preparation a little differently, to see if I can manage a more all-round successful race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;For my first time, I followed a training plan, a sensible decision I thought, except I have a tendency to get a little obsessive and found myself following it a bit too strictly at times, scared to deviate from it even if I was exhausted or had an injury coming on. I was already a fairly experienced distance runner but during my marathon training, my weekly mileage shot up to an average of 50 miles a week with my longest week at just shy of 70 miles. This was a big difference from my usual 30 miles and looking back at my plan now, I wonder how I didn't completely fall apart. I ended up with plantar fascitiis among other injuries but instead of resting, I largely ignored them and kept going. Additionally, not a lot of my training was comprised of easy/steady running, I did hard workouts back-to-back such as 10km tempo on a Friday night followed by a Parkrun the next morning. I can see now that this approach gave me very little time to recover and was actually detrimental to my training. I was also a bit over-enthusiastic on my long runs. Most sources I have found suggest going up to 20 miles, however I decided on 22 miles and I had a tendency to push too hard on what should have been easy runs. This just meant that by the time I got to the actual marathon, I was exhausted, had lingering injuries and found it a lot harder than my training performances would have suggested, struggling by about 15 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;This time however, I haven't followed a written training plan. Obviously I still respect the difficulty of a marathon and have made sure to gradually increase my weekly mileage, just not to quite the same extent. I'm at just over 50km a week so far, rather than 50 miles! While I haven't had planned sessions, I've kept track of everything I've done and made sure to include a weekly long run up to 20 miles, some tempo sessions, a bit of fartlek and recovery runs, plus rest days(!). I've never been very good at rest days and would often do a session the day after a long run, but this time, if I feel too tired, I'll have a rest day or two instead of pushing through it. So far, this approach seems to have worked; I haven't any injuries and no plantar fasciitis. I'm taking this as an encouraging sign that I might have found a better way of training, for me at least, although only the marathon event itself will tell me if I'm correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;With any luck, I may have learnt from some of my rookie first-time errors and hopefully this will lead to a more successful marathon attempt this time around. I'll try to be more strict with my taper, not to eat too late the night before and, crucially, not to set off too fast! However, part of this experiment involves not placing too much expectation on the actual event - 'casual' marathon training as I have been calling it - so I'll just have to see what happens on the day!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">So, a little while ago I decided it was time to attempt another marathon. As you'll know if you've read my previous post My first marathon, I ran the Nottingham marathon almost exactly two years ago and in hindsight, I made a lot of rookie errors. This time, with the experience of one under my running belt, I want to try to do my preparation a little differently, to see if I can manage a more all-round successful race.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">REASONS TO LIVE IN NEW ZEALAND (AND TO BE CHEERFUL!)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/new%20zealand/travel/2016/07/18/reasons-to-live-in-new-zealand.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="REASONS TO LIVE IN NEW ZEALAND (AND TO BE CHEERFUL!)" /><published>2016-07-18T22:06:19+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-18T22:06:19+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/new%20zealand/travel/2016/07/18/reasons-to-live-in-new-zealand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/new%20zealand/travel/2016/07/18/reasons-to-live-in-new-zealand.html">&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;New Zealand, Aotearoa, Land of the Long White Cloud…these are just a few of the names for these little islands lying way down here in the Tasman Sea. The country is pretty much as far away as you can get from the UK, literally on the other side on the world, which does make it feel like a good place to escape to. It seems at the moment that barely a day goes by without news of political upheaval, acts of violence and terrorist threats, which makes New Zealand feel like a safe little paradise, quiet, calm and relaxed. Of course, I'm not saying the country is perfect, it still has its issues but especially right now, it's pretty awesome. In fact, quite a few of the people I know who moved here temporarily at about the same time I did are all still here and don't really want to leave!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;It's Beautiful...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;One reason, for me at least, is that the country is beautiful. Having grown up living nowhere near the sea, being able to just wander down to the harbour and look out over the sea (which is always a blue-green colour rather than the murky grey of the English Channel) and the mountains is one of my favourite things about living in Wellington. Climb up to Mount Victoria or go up to one of the hilltop suburbs and you are rewarded with panoramic views over the city and harbour. Go slightly further afield to the City to Sea Walkway or Mount Kaukau and you can see the edge of the Queen Charlotte Sound in the distance, the gateway to the South Island. Outside of the capital, the scenery only gets better, with the rolling hills and remote forest parks, the raw coastline and quiet beaches. The South Island though is where it gets really dramatic. Mountains, glaciers, sounds and fjords, pristine sandy beaches and brilliantly blue sea are just a few of the best bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;The Culture Is Awesome...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;The Kiwi culture is also part of what makes New Zealand great. As far as I can tell, Kiwis are very proud of their country and are generally friendly people. Despite being the capital city, Wellington is a small place and feels like you can't go out without seeing someone you recognise, hardly the 'big city' atmosphere. This is where &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shegoesplacesandseesthings.com/travel/auckland-the-big-city/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Auckland&lt;/a&gt; 
comes in; the population of nearly 1.5 million people is massive in comparison and it feels much more like a bustling city with busy streets and all the big shops. The M&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:'Sans Serif';&quot;&gt;ā&lt;/span&gt;ori culture is also very prominent throughout New Zealand and well-respected. The language is spoken by many people and lots of phrases - '&lt;strong&gt;Kia Ora&lt;/strong&gt;', '&lt;strong&gt;whanau&lt;/strong&gt;' (family) and '&lt;strong&gt;kai&lt;/strong&gt;' (food) - are commonly used in Kiwi English as well. M&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:'Sans Serif';&quot;&gt;ā&lt;/span&gt;ori stories are also well-known, a few that I've learnt about include the tale of M&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:'Sans Serif';&quot;&gt;ā&lt;/span&gt;ui and how he fished up the North Island (&lt;strong&gt;Te Ika a M&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:'Sans Serif';&quot;&gt;ā&lt;/span&gt;ui&lt;/strong&gt; – the fish of M&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:'Sans Serif';&quot;&gt;ā&lt;/span&gt;ui) from his &lt;strong&gt;waka&lt;/strong&gt; (canoe) that became the South Island (&lt;strong&gt;Te Waka a M&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:'Sans Serif';&quot;&gt;ā&lt;/span&gt;ui&lt;/strong&gt;) and the love story of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shegoesplacesandseesthings.com/travel/rotorua/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tutanekai and Hinemoa&lt;/a&gt;, centred on Mokoia Island in Lake Rotorua.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;The Not-So-Great Bits...&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Of course, there are a few not-so-great things about living in New Zealand. It's expensive, especially food and drink. A beer in a bar will set you back at least $8 (roughly £4.00) and that's not even for a full, UK standard pint. Fruit, vegetables and meat are all also incredibly pricey, despite the fact that the country produces a lot of the latter, so the cost of living can be pretty high. Additionally, there is a noticeable lack of central heating and homes tend not to be well-insulated, which is odd, as New Zealand has pretty chilly winters! Then there's the small matter that it's expensive and time-consuming to get to, being on the other side of the world. A minimum of twenty-four hours on a plane and huge time difference doesn't make it easy – if you thought Australia was a long way away, try sitting on a plane for another three hours past Sydney! In general though, New Zealand is a great place to live compared to a lot of places and one that I'm glad I made a temporary home.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="New Zealand" /><summary type="html">New Zealand, Aotearoa, Land of the Long White Cloud…these are just a few of the names for these little islands lying way down here in the Tasman Sea. The country is pretty much as far away as you can get from the UK, literally on the other side on the world, which does make it feel like a good place to escape to. It seems at the moment that barely a day goes by without news of political upheaval, acts of violence and terrorist threats, which makes New Zealand feel like a safe little paradise, quiet, calm and relaxed. Of course, I'm not saying the country is perfect, it still has its issues but especially right now, it's pretty awesome. In fact, quite a few of the people I know who moved here temporarily at about the same time I did are all still here and don't really want to leave!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NEW ZEALAND’S TOP SCENIC SPOTS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/new%20zealand/travel/2016/07/14/new-zealands-top-scenic-spots.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NEW ZEALAND'S TOP SCENIC SPOTS" /><published>2016-07-14T23:02:03+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-14T23:02:03+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/new%20zealand/travel/2016/07/14/new-zealands-top-scenic-spots</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/new%20zealand/travel/2016/07/14/new-zealands-top-scenic-spots.html">&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;New Zealand is well known for its stunning natural beauty and diverse landscapes, which are reasons why so many tourists and backpackers want to visit. From the many places that I've now visited, here are a few that I think are among the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Aoraki/Mount Cook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/front-page/aoraki.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aoraki/Mt Cook&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Mount Cook (known as Aoraki in M&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:'Sans Serif';&quot;&gt;ā&lt;/span&gt;ori) is the highest mountain in New Zealand, standing at 3,724 metres and it is impressive both from the ground and from 16,000 feet up! The walk along the Hooker Valley track from Mount Cook Village leads to one of the most gorgeous views I have ever seen, with the mountain perfectly reflected, in good weather at least, in the glacial lake in front of it. Standing by the water's edge gives a sense of the enormous scale of the mountains and glaciers surrounding you. From above, the landscape is equally striking. Skydiving over the Fox Glacier allows you to see the country's highest peak and glaciers from a more unusual angle. From so high up, you are treated to a panoramic view of Mount Cook and right out over the West coast, which is definitely worth jumping out of an aeroplane for!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Tongariro Alpine Crossing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/front-page/tongariro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Emerald Lakes&quot; width=&quot;430&quot; height=&quot;330&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;The Tongariro Alpine Crossing is a very popular 19.4 km day hike around Mt Tongariro, Mt Ruapehu and Mt Ngauruhoe, which tends to feature pretty highly on backpacking itineraries. The trail passes through volcanic and alpine terrain with highlights including the Emerald Lakes, Red Crater and views out over the central North Island. While it does require a decent level of fitness to cope with the mountainous terrain for 6-8 hours, the walk is pretty accessible and I've seen everyone from children to parents with baby backpacks to older folk taking it on. If you've got time, take a detour to the summit of Mt Tongariro, where if it isn't too cloudy, you will be treated to some brilliant views over the somewhat lunar landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Queenstown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/front-page/queenstownhill.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Queenstown Hill&quot; width=&quot;430&quot; height=&quot;330&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Queenstown, known as the adventure capital of the country, is set in some incredibly picturesque surroundings. Lake Wakatipu, surrounded by the Remarkables mountains, often resembles a painting or photograph. The contrast of the rocky slopes rising from the deep blue water looks even more magical at sunset when the skies become streaked with pink and orange. The view from the top of the Gondola station, 450 metres above Queenstown, gives the feeling of looking over a toy-town, with the Botanic Gardens jutting out into the lake and paragliders often gracing the skies. From up there, you also get a sense of how enormous the lake is, nestled around the mountains. Another good vantage point is from the summit of Queenstown Hill where not only can you see Lake Wakatipu, but also the Shotover Valley behind you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Punakaiki Pancake Rocks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;The Punakaiki Pancake Rocks are an incredible geological feature found on the South Island's West Coast. The rocky columns, arches and blowholes formed from layers of limestone over thousands of years extend along the coastline and out into the ocean, the waves spraying upwards as they collide with the rocks. There is a short loop walkway along the cliff edge to allow a close-up view of this popular natural phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Punakaiki.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pancake Rocks&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Milford Sound&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/front-page/milfordsound.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;milford&quot; width=&quot;415&quot; height=&quot;306&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;A boat trip through Milford Sound really is a New Zealand classic and features on many itineraries. While far from being the only sound or fjord, it is the most famous and definitely draws the crowds despite its remote location. The imposing Mitre Peak soars almost 1700m into the skies, surrounded by seemingly vertical cliff faces rising from the deep waters. If you're lucky, you may see dolphins and fur seals and the odd kayaker will put into perspective just how enormous the sound is. Boat cruises here are very popular though so don't be too surprised to find yourself in amongst a lot of camera-toting tourists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Inter-Island Ferry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:right; padding-left:30px&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ferry.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ferry&quot; width=&quot;470&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;While not exactly a destination, the ferry ride between the North and South Islands is without a doubt the most scenic ferry trip I've ever taken. The journey takes three hours to cross the Cook Strait, from the capital city Wellington in the North over to Picton in the South. Watching Wellington harbour fading into the distance is pretty enough but the real treat comes when the boat begins to wind through the Queen Charlotte Sounds. Around a hour of the crossing is spent in these waters and you'll want to make sure you're out on the deck to take in the views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Waimangu Volcanic Valley&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;Waimangu, near Rotorua, shows off nature at its finest and wildest. Volcanic landscapes, geothermal hot springs, mineral formations and blue, green and pink lakes are among the best features here and it's well worth spending the day exploring the trails through the valley. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shegoesplacesandseesthings.com/travel/rotorua/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Visit Rotorua&lt;/a&gt; for more on the valley and to see what's on offer elsewhere in Rotorua.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Waimangu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Waimangu&quot; width=&quot;460&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; class=&quot;img-rounded&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="New Zealand" /><category term="North Island" /><category term="South Island" /><summary type="html">New Zealand is well known for its stunning natural beauty and diverse landscapes, which are reasons why so many tourists and backpackers want to visit. From the many places that I've now visited, here are a few that I think are among the best.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Ultra Dream</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/running/2016/07/08/my-ultra-dream.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Ultra Dream" /><published>2016-07-08T05:51:32+01:00</published><updated>2016-07-08T05:51:32+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/running/2016/07/08/my-ultra-dream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/running/2016/07/08/my-ultra-dream.html">&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;For a while now, I've thought that ultra marathons sound pretty cool. I have no doubts that they are brutally painful, exhausting beyond belief and a big time commitment, but still, I'd love to give one a go. There is something very alluring about the idea of running for hours along remote trails through beautiful countryside, pushing my body to its absolute limits, seeing what it's capable of. Having run a marathon, I have a little bit of experience of long distance training and an idea of the pain and mental focus required. I've often heard endurance runners say that state of mind is vital to success in long races, and from my experiences so far, it's true. Negative thoughts can destroy a run while believing in what you're doing can have a far bigger impact on performance than you might think; whenever I'm having a bad run, I find smiling to myself (okay, full-on grinning if no-one's watching) helps, to remind me that I'm enjoying it really. However, I've still only done this for three or four hours at a time at the most, usually just one or two. It hardly compares to spending all night on your feet, unable to guarantee finishing until you actually cross the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;I am aware that not too many people share this dream, in fact I think that everyone I know, even fellow long distance runners, thinks I'm crazy to even entertain the idea. Recently I've been reading a couple of books by the American ultra runner Dean Karnazes, who seems to think nothing of running literally all night through the San Franciscan hills, and have found myself inspired to want to run ultra distances. One excerpt I particularly remember is him describing how, midway through an all-night run, he got a pizza ordered to the side of the road and then ran along eating it! What I also like about the books is that he doesn't glorify the sport; the pain, blood, sweat and tears is right there on the surface. Yes, he talks about running until you pass out but also about some of the wonderful travel experiences and camaraderie involved in the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;western&quot; align=&quot;JUSTIFY&quot;&gt;I usually receive nervous looks whenever I mention ultra running, as though I might just one day bounce out of the door to run 100 miles. I understand that it sounds like a worrying thing to do and pushing your body to the extreme is hardly safe. All I could think about, for instance, when I crossed the line of a rather warm half-marathon was salt...I was very dehydrated, unable to really speak coherently or walk in a straight line, after 13 miles. After my marathon, I was just exhausted. Every leg muscle burned, my toes were on fire and all I wanted to do was lie down, even food didn't appeal. My first words on finishing were that I never wanted to run again, my parents just laughed at me, knowing this wasn't true and of course it wasn't. Within a week I was trying to jog again and it didn't take long to get back into it. Now, nearly two years later, I've decided it's time to run another one. I know that I need much more marathon experience before I even think about attempting an ultra and I'm in no particular rush, I'd rather build up to it and be able to enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For a while now, I've thought that ultra marathons sound pretty cool. I have no doubts that they are brutally painful, exhausting beyond belief and a big time commitment, but still, I'd love to give one a go. There is something very alluring about the idea of running for hours along remote trails through beautiful countryside, pushing my body to its absolute limits, seeing what it's capable of. Having run a marathon, I have a little bit of experience of long distance training and an idea of the pain and mental focus required. I've often heard endurance runners say that state of mind is vital to success in long races, and from my experiences so far, it's true. Negative thoughts can destroy a run while believing in what you're doing can have a far bigger impact on performance than you might think; whenever I'm having a bad run, I find smiling to myself (okay, full-on grinning if no-one's watching) helps, to remind me that I'm enjoying it really. However, I've still only done this for three or four hours at a time at the most, usually just one or two. It hardly compares to spending all night on your feet, unable to guarantee finishing until you actually cross the line.</summary></entry></feed>